# HENRY S. NAVARRO

+1 510 378 2435 | henrysnavarro@icloud.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer and UX Designer and Technical Leader with 20+ years of applied industry experience. Unique combination of technical and design skills. Specializes in web applications frontend and capable of full-stack development. Proficient in systems architecture, security, performance, human factors, technology evaluation, process improvement and best practices. Academic backgrounds in Physics, Human Computer Interaction, Business and Multimedia. Life-long commitment to continuous personal improvement and innovation.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Blockchain Expert, Blockchain Council 2019 Cryptocurrency Expert, Blockchain Council 2019 Predix Architect and Developer, General Electric 2018 Scrum Master and Product Owner, Scrum Alliance 2016 Essential Leadership Skills, General Electric 2015 Human Computer Interaction, Iowa State University 2012 Flex Expert, Adobe Systems 2009

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS, NodeJS, jQuery, Polymer, Web Components, AngularJS, Git, ActionScript, SQL, NoSQL, UNIX Shell Scripts, Single-Page Applications, Micro-Services, Agile (Scrum), Behavior/Test-Driven Development, Design Thinking, UX Design, Rapid Prototyping, Build Automation, Threat Modeling, Data Visualization, Technical Documentation.

## **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

- Blockchain, Cryptocurrency
- Internet of Things (IoT)
- Renewable Energy
- Healthcare
- E-Learning

- Online Video and Advertising
- Developer Training
- Bioinformatics
- Manufacturing Systems

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PRIVATE STARTUP, MAR 2019 - MAY 2019

 Designs and develops web application frontend using AngularJS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 for a Cryptocurrency Intelligence system that monitors blockchain risks.

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PRIVATE STARTUP, OCT 2018 - MAR 2019

 Designs and develops web application frontend using ReactJS, React-Redux, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 for a Blockchain system used for the launch and sale of tokenized securities

## SENIOR DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST, GE DIGITAL, NOV 2015-MAY 2018

- Led frontend development of accelerator applications, authored learning guides and facilitated developer on-boarding and adoption of company solutions.
- Designed, developed and enhanced re-usable web components used in multiple applications for company's solution portfolio
- Created infographics and diagrams that effectively convey how company's solutions worked
- Drove developer adoption through code samples, forum answers and hands-on mentorship
- Implemented projects using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, NodeJS, ReactJS, jQuery, PolymerJS, Web Components, Git, Gulp and various other libraries
- Consistently performed beyond annual goals

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GE HEALTHCARE, AUG 2014 - NOV 2015

- Designed and implemented web applications modules and UI components for GE's Centricity 360, its main cloud-based healthcare solution offering
- Designed and coded modules that became standard for frontend security in web applications
- Occupied role as main UX resource for engineering team, effectively managing issues at the intersection of design and technology
- Mentored junior engineers on various topics such as code organization, design patterns, team processes
- Completed trainings in organizational leadership
- Performed beyond annual goals

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ABB - POWER ONE, SEP 2012 - JUL 2014

 Enhanced web application frontend of company's main product offering for managing solar panel arrays

- Created interactive prototypes of user interface components for next generation of company's main web application offering
- Occupied role as main UX resource for entire engineering team, created icon sets, provided design opinions

#### SENIOR UI DEVELOPER, SERENA SOFTWARE, NOV 2010 - APR 2012

Developed and maintained web application front-end, consulted with designers and product managers, testers and technical writers. Designed and maintained iconography for company's main software product. I was considered as the main resource for usability and user experience in the projects I participated in.

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GLOBALENGLISH, SEP 2009 - APR 2010

Developed and maintained rich internet applications. Consulted with product designers, UX designers, product management and quality assurance. Improved asset development and deployment with the use of better software tools and identification of process inefficiencies and corresponding fixes.

#### SENIOR WEB APPLICATIONS ENGINEER, CBS, APR 2008 - SEP 2009

Developed and maintained rich internet applications. Consulted with product designers, UX designers, product management and quality assurance. Developed code modules for integrating company's software with partner advertising content. Worked with company partners and external customers on technical details software integration. Led the architecture and development of the company's first robust online video streaming client software.

(Additional employment history details available upon request)

## **EDUCATION**

IOWA STATE UNIVERSITY – GRADUATE CERTIFICATE IN HCI, 2012

CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY – SUBJECTS IN MBA, 2005

U.C. SANTA CRUZ EXTENSION – CERTIFICATE IN COMPUTER NETWORKS, 1999

ATENEO DE MANILA UNIVERSITY, BACHELORS IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING, 1992

ATENEO DE MANILA UNIVERSITY, BACHELORS IN PHYSICS, 1991

## PROFILE / PORTFOLIO

www.linkedin.com/in/henrynavarro www.github.com/henrysnavarro www.github.com/henrysnavarro/designs